The survival of Oswald Danes
turns out to be
the first incident
in a much bigger story.
The amazing thing about the miracle
is not that no-one's dying,
it's not that the human race
has become immortal,
it's that it happened
to everyone at the same time.
So now what we have accumulating are
people who should be dead but aren't.
We have to start manufacturing
painkillers immediately.
Jilly Kitzinger, Mr Danes.
- I'm something of a talent spotter.
- I don't need you.
I disagree, Mr Danes.
Someone's trying to erase Torchwood.
What if they 're also trying
to erase anyone
who's ever had
any contact with Torchwood?
Go get him.
I have a car.
REX: All right, just drive. Drive, drive.
What the hell is going on?
Welcome to Torchwood.
What happened to you in there?
Something happened to all of us,
not just me.
Miracle Day arrived, and...
we all came out of it changed.
But why do you think
people accept you as an expert?
I-I'm no expert, but...
I'm a free man.
And since the miracle,
the White House has said nothing,
scientists have said nothing.
I think the establishment
is scared into silence.
I survived. I can say what I want.
Such as?
Well, is anyone paying attention
to the profits
that the drug companies are making?
We need drugs more than ever.
But I think we should take
all those pills
and those tablets and those potions,
and give them to people free.
Yes, that's what I'm saying,
because that's how radical
the world needs to be right now.
Free drugs, free healthcare,
free access for all.
INTERVIEWER: You really think
that's practical?
DAN ES: Who's to say what's practical
any more? That's pre-miracle thinking.
- Who told you to set me up?
- Rex!
- P-Put the gun down.
- Because everywhere I turn,
the whole CIA has been poisoned against
me, by you! Who told you to do it?!
- I don't know what you mean.
- Bullshit!
You set me up, Friedkin,
and you got paid to do it.
Now, technically,
we both know that I can't “kill" you.
But you see, the beauty
of this miracle is, if I shoot you
just right,
then maybe you might live in agony
for...who knows how long?
Maybe 1,000 years?
Now, you think about that,
because I've always wondered
what part of the brain is memories...
...or personality...
or what lets you control
your own bladder?
- No, don't!
- Tell me!
I-I-I don't know who they are.
I never did.
They just paid me over the years.
They've been there for decades,
and I can't...
couldn't stop them. I mean, it's too late.
Look, they've...they've only ever
contacted me on one telephone number.
- Get the number.
- Yes, I know that. Thanks.
Yeah, well, hurry up. I was right about
the alarm. The police are on their way.
- Est/refs tracking them.
- Er...confirmed.
There's a unit on 5th
- heading for Riverdale.
- North or south?
North. I mean,
heading from the north going south.
Gwen, one car from the north.
On it. Doing it.
They only contact me.
They call me through that.
But listen, Rex,
you won't find them.
[never did.
They're everywhere.
They know everything.
Well, I just have one more thing to say.
- Don't go deaf.
- What?
You took your time.
One unit on Tacoma.
Jack, you'd better move.
They're right on top of you.
Go, go, go, go, 90!
Not bad, team.
- Not bad at all.
- What did we get?
We got a cellphone. So, whoever made
the miracle, now we've got contact.
anything? Any news?
JACK: Yeah. Don't worry, it's good.
They've moved Rhys and Anwen
to a safe house, location unknown,
but they're in the custody
of Sergeant Andy Davidson.
We've got his number. Have you called him?
That line's been decommissioned.
- I'm trying, OK?
- OK, that's my bloody family, so hurry!
Right, here we go.
Brand-new mobiles for everyone,
courtesy of Jack's cashpoint card.
I hope I didn't clear you out.
Not a chance. That account's been
gathering interest since 1906.
And some new clothes, just some basics.
If they don't fit, then tough. Jack.
And food. Everybody is panic buying,
so I had to go to the petrol station,
and all they had was crisps.
Oh, I think you meant
gas station and chips.
Crisps are called chips over here.
Thank you, Miss Translation.
Oh, and a mobile is a cellphone,
and by cashpoint, I think you mean ATM.
Don't ever leave my side, OK?
It is absolutely mental out there.
Some TV show said the miracle was a virus,
then some website said it was the plague,
so they all run to the shops
and clear the shelves.
Oh, and the new cult
out on the street, that march...
they call themselves...the Soulless.
Apparently, everlasting life
has robbed mankind of their souls.
Oh, it turns out Friedkin
was telling the truth.
His handset was only contacted
by one number.
- I traced it, but it hits a vine.
- What's a vine?
A vine is when you trace a number back,
but the trail branches out,
then it branches out again and again.
Piggyback those secondary numbers
spreading out almost exponentially.
So, instead of tracing one number,
you're chasing 500,000.
What?
- You should be in the hospital.
- Hey, less of the sympathy.
He can keep working, the bastard!
You're gonna keep just going on and on
about your kid, huh?
Do you want her here with us? Hmm?
Maybe she can go play in that corner,
where the lead paint chips
look extra tasty.
Got you that from your mates,
the Soulless.
- Did you get me painkillers?
- Sold out. Unlucky.
But I think we should take all those pills
and those tablets and those potions,
and give them to people free.
See? Now, this guy has got a good idea -
free drugs.
- So, who is this guy...Oswald Danes?
- Ah, he just got lucky.
He's a convicted murderer and paedophile
sentenced to death on Miracle Day.
All the same, he's on every channel.
We need to investigate anyone
who's making a profit out of this.
- On it, doing it.
- So go back, search family history,
- everything...
- I know.
Thank you, I know what I'm doing.
And this lemonade is flat.
It's lemonade.
It's supposed to be flat.
- What, fizzy, fizzy lemonade?!
- It's fizzy in the UK and flat in the US.
- Hmm, just about sums it up.
- How are we doing on the money?
I can't trace
where the bribes came from,
but I'm going through Friedkin's
patterns of behaviour instead.
He's a section chief.
You're not getting into those files.
Hm, really? You want to bet?
This Torchwood software, it's serious.
- What are you doing with that?
- Nothing.just putting my numbers in.
- Whose numbers?
- My sister's.
You're going to phone your sister?
- No...
- Esther,
what the hell is the matter with you?
Don't you know how serious this is?
The CIA is gonna be monitoring
- her calls.
- I'm sorry, OK?
- Well, think next time!
- Come on, Rex. She's not used to this.
Well, I'm not used to this either.
It doesn't make me stupid.
- That's enough, OK?
- And who the hell put you in charge?
I think the CIA did.
You're a member of Torchwood now,
whether you like it or not.
I'm sorry, OK? I really am. I just...
I've never done all this before,
and you guys have.
I sit at my desk
and read blogs for a living.
Rex, it's my sister. She's just...
She's not well.
Yeah, it's irrelevant.
I tried to do a search on morphic fields,
cos that's the best
that I could work out,
that some sort of morphic field
suspended the human race.
- But...oh, it's got to be more than that.
- What do you mean?
It's like there's some sort of energy
behind this,
a will, a drive, a consciousness,
cos this miracle, it's more than
people just surviving. They are so alive.
You saw Lyn, that woman at the airport.
She should have been paralysed,
but she just kept on going.
And I've seen bodies at the morgue
burnt and broken,
still alive, staring right at me.
They weren't even allowed
to be unconscious.
It's as if something is willing them
to go on,
each and every individual,
forced into life.
That was me...
all the way through my accident...
wide awake.
And you could feel everything
that happened? It still hurt?
Yeah.
So what did the search say?
Well, that's the problem.
Everybody's had the same idea.
"Morphic field"...
...gets 10 million results.
Then I'll go through them,
all 10 million.
See, that's what I do
when I'm at my desk. Hard work.
I know.
- He cockblocked the ATF.
- I have no idea what any of that means.
The ATF is the Bureau of Alcohol,
Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.
They asked the CIA about information
on a warehouse here in Washington,
but Friedkin forwarded the request
on to ancillary three times.
GWEN: What's ancillary?
It's a paper chase, a guaranteed way
to lose something in the system.
So, if he tried to stop people
from seeing the warehouse,
then maybe he was paid to protect it,
which would indicate
there's something in there.
- It's at 3rd and Boston, south-west.
- All right, so we've got a mission.
First thing we need to do
is steal a new car.
Er...ahem!
So who's giving the orders?
OK, Torchwood, what do you say?
We need to steal a new car.
-
- Got one!
REX: Oh, there's somebody's
dry-cleaning back here.
And it's my size. I'm taking
these. My clothes are stinking.
Ladies, avert your eyes.
That includes you, World War II.
These new phones aren't bad.
The camera is good quality, too.
I know you didn'tjust take a picture
of me changing my pants.
- You're changing your pants?
- Pants mean trousers.
Are we really on a mission here?
Yeah, well, maybe this is the way
Torchwood does things, mate.
Yeah, well, maybe you want to drive
on the other side of the street, "mate".
Mmm.
ESTHER: 3rd and Boston. That's the one.
Security profile says
the guard's on a quarterly rotation.
That means he checks in with base
every 15 minutes starting on the hour.
All right, so we gonna come up
with a plan, or is that just
the American thing to do?
- Hi.
- What can I do for you?
- Er, I wonder, can you help?
- Sure.
We're a little bit lost. Sorry.
The British abroad - hopeless, honestly!
But I think...
We're trying to get to Boston Avenue.
Is it Boston...
Boston Road or Boston...?
Is it Boston Street?
Oh!
- You've done that before.
- So many times.
- Esther, how much time do we have?
- 77 minutes.
I can unlock it, but only by tricking it
into thinking it's booting up for the day,
but that means all the lights will
come on, the computers will boot up.
REX: Do it.
- Esther, keep watch.
- Right.
Let's see what's in this.
Let me see that.
It's drugs.
-  It's legitimate drugs.
- What is it?
Metanec. Metanec is a painkiller, yeah?
Hallelujah!
- Thousands of them. Millions of them.
- PhiCorp.
Yeah, you know PhiCorp, Jack -
PhiCorp's a big pharmaceutical company.
We've got PhiCorp back home.
It's everywhere, it's worldwide.
These are the same pills I've been taking.
The beauty of it is they're non-narcotic.
They keep you painless and wide awake.
It's the perfect drug
for the new world order.
There was a delivery yesterday.
When was the first one?
Way back.
Oh. Oh, hold on.
Deliveries go back at least a year,
all for drugs.
All from PhiCorp.
Oh, my God!
JACK: Bigger on the inside
than the outside.
GWEN: These are all painkillers?
- They're ready for a war.
- No.
They were ready for the miracle.
PhiCorp knew it was coming.
You, come here.
This woman's husband strangled her.
She doesn't die, so he keeps
strangling her. Now her brain is soup,
her hyoid bone - her neck - is like dust,
and you're telling me
- that's not murder?
- We've charged him with assault.
Well, that's not enough!
This is what murder looks like now!
Don't blame me. We're not even allowed
to say "attempted murder" any more,
cos murder's impossible.
The whole system's breaking down.
It's the NIH. They say you're late
for some kind of panel.
MAN: I'm looking at an additional
half million people a day.
What's up?
The 50% of pregnancies that
spontaneously abort are not aborting.
- Genetic mistakes are suddenly viable.
- No baby is a mistake.
- Oh!
- What hospital are you from?
- Providence. Dr Carey Murphy.
- Yeah, I was a Catholic too, once.
I got better. We're talking brain outside
the skull, no skin, no face, suffering.
- Yeah, these are mistakes.
-
Oh, hell. Sorry.
Um, but actually, I think
we can help. Jilly Kitzinger. Hi.
Pain management in newborns is something
we've already got going on at PhiCorp,
- so we can roll out a strategy.
- Fine. We've got a bigger problem.
Somebody got off a plane
from New Delhi in Boston
last night, and now we've got cholera.
I warned you!
I seem to recall no shortage
of clean water in Boston.
Turn on a tap, gentlemen. Can we talk
about the situation in the ERs?
And I'm going to keep warning you -
we'll see more of this every day.
DR ROSENBLOOM: We're not done
with the birth issue, guys.
They're putting contraceptives
in the water supply in India,
mainland China. That's something
we might have to look at here.
That's not a serious proposition?
It doesn't matter what happens in the long
term if we lose our healthcare system now.
We need more facilities, more space,
but who's gonna organise it?
DR ROSENBLOOM: We'll put it on the agenda,
but I think
we're getting pretty far off track here.
Can we talk about the contraception option
with some professional distance, please?
It's been raining on and off.
Oh! Like it wasn't
end-of-the-worldly enough.
We don't deserve this miracle.
We're just gonna screw it up,
like we always do.
Human damn beings.
And I'm including myself.
PhiCorp needs feedback
from medical staff.
Why don't you come and talk to us?
- My schedule is a little full.
- OK.
That's fine. But you gave
a commencement speech
last year at Columbia
about your college mentor,
how she worked for
Doctors Without Borders
when they were just starting out
in Biafra. You said
you wanted to find a way to give back,
like she did. Did you find that?
I... I was talking about fieldwork.
Everything's fieldwork now.
I mean, FEMA...FEMA is...hopeless.
It's a pot of glue that still thinks
it's a racehorse.
PhiCorp can really do something.
You're just out to make a profit.
Well, companies profit by turning
situations around to their advantage.
But isn't that how every human
damn being gets through their day?
Come in
and say hello.
Just once.
- Maybe.
- I'll take that as a yes!
Oh, God. I gotta go. Busy, busy.
But you have my card
and you won't regret it.
And that's a promise.
OK, we do a deep search
on this PhiCorp.
I wanna peel back security
and find everything.
- I can handle company history.
- I can do European operations.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
After we do all this research,
then what do we do?
We go in, whether that means
infiltration or confrontation.
So, we're just gonna
sit on this information?
Come on, guys, seriously?
I mean, we've got a major link
between an international corporation
and the miracle,
and we're just gonna
keep it to ourselves?
We got this far on our own.
Yeah, but see, it's not just about us.
Not any more.
This is about doing the right thing...
- for the state and for the people.
- Jack, he's got a point.
OK. We need a friend
with connections. Got any ideas?
REX: All right.
My senior instructor at Langley. I'm
pretty sure he'd still give me a chance.
- He's CIA.
- He's ex-CIA.
Look, I know this is a risk.
I know that.
But it's a risk I'm willing to take.
So what do you say?
OK.
And I've got proof.
I've got photographs
and documentation.
But I can't compromise you
or your family, sir.
You know I would never do that.
So maybe we could meet
somewhere neutral.
How about the lobby
of the Freeville Hotel?
It's on North Street West.
The Free ville Hotel.
Damn.
REX: What's the use?
We discover this PhiCorp shit,
but everyone's been turned against us.
We're still on the run.
We can't trust anyone.
But they can't have got
to everyone we know
and they can't be tracking
the cellphones, cos they're new.
I warned you. Whoever these people are,
they're good
and they're ready for us,
which puts us back at square one.
We tackle PhiCorp ourselves.
And is that standard Torchwood policy?
Suppose it is, yeah.
You know, you...you dress
like it's World War II,
so I don't expect you
to be up on current events,
but there is no Torchwood!
It's dead.
Gone. Buried.
It's us!
As far as I can see,
you got all your staff killed.
They were my friends.
- Your dead friends!
- ESTHER: Rex, don't.
" Rex, don't"!
Ah, you want me to stop? I'll stop.
Who the hell are you people anyway?
Rex, hold on. Hold on. We've got
to work together on this, Rex.
Don't, Rex. Don't!
Don't! Rex!
City's going wild.
Everyone's out drinking.
Nobody knows whether it's a party
- or a wake.
-JACK: My arm is itching.
Poor baby.
- I think it's infected.
- You're worse than Rhys.
It's itching because it's healing.
Now, stop it, Jack.
Oi, Jack!
Mortal man...mortal needs.
Yeah, we've got work to do.
I am so mortal.
Hey, baby! What's up?
Yeah! Whoo!
There's a poem.
"I have been one
acquainted with the night.
"I have walked out in rain
and back in rain."
It's probably not about walking.
I suppose it's about death.
Yeah. The poets are the ones
who are really gonna suffer, aren't they?
All those poems about death.
Well, it was Robert Frost,
so maybe it really was just about walking.
Oh...
My apartment's that way.
Ten minutes down the freeway,
turn off at 11th.
- Home.
- You'd be arrested on the spot.
And that'd be worse than this?
I'd be safe,
be warm.
Wouldn't be holding you back.
I don't know if I can do this.
What's wrong with your sister?
She's not sick. She just...
...can't cope.
Never could. I'm the youngest,
but I've always...
looked after her.
Well...
she's in that direction.
But I'm warning you, you give up now
and you'll prove that Rex was right.
Can't have that.
No, we can't.
- "Miles to go before we sleep."
- Mm-hm.
Scotch.
What are these?
Sobriety chips.
Got two-month chips, six-month chips.
I think I've got a whole bowl of
ten-year chips around here somewhere.
People are throwing a lot of sober
out the window tonight.
Sorry I can't add to your collection.
Unless you want a button.
Oh, you damage that coat,
I'm jumping over this bar to protect it.
Jack.
You like the coat?
Brad.
Passionately.
What's the latest from the White House,
Candice?
Are we getting any sort of clarity?
Well, off the record George,
this miracle is so impossible,
a lot of high-level officials
are thinking the word "alien",
meaning an intervention or at least
an influence from beyond this world.
But so far still,
no-one's willing to say it out loud.
Well, bringing the discussion
back down from outer space,
we saw some action today.
The Supreme Court has agreed to hear
a case asking for adjustments
to the life sentences
of convicted criminals,
because these days, how long is life?
CANDICE: Right, the argument is
that a life sentence
is now potentially infinite.
Tomorrow we've got Oswald Danes
in our Atlanta studio ...
- It's OK?
- Mm-hm.
For the trumpet shall sound,
and the dead shall be raised
incorruptible,
and we shall be changed.
For this corruptible body
must put on incorruption,
and this mortal
shall put on immortality.
So when this corruptible
shall have put on incorruption,
and the mortal
shall have put on immortality,
then shall he brought to pass
the saying which is written -
"Death shall be swallowed up in victory.
"0 death, where is thy sting?
0 grave, where is thy victory?"
REX: Dr Juarez.
I'm gonna need you
to dress this again.
And I'm afraid
I'm gonna have to insist.
I'm gonna need your help.
You know, medicine and care...
just until I clear my name.
I'm just taking your word for it
that you're not a traitor.
Oh, yeah.
But you know,
you've already given me drugs,
taken me into your home.
You know, we both have the power
to make a case against one another.
- Nice.
- Yeah.
So, what you're saying is,
that's what our relationship
comes down to - blackmail.
Huh! Well...
...when you put it that way...
...it's kinda hot.
Rex...
I'm exhausted.
Me too.
The sting of death is sin,
and the sake of sin is the law!
But thanks be to Goal
which giveth us our victory
through our Lord jesus Christ'.
Hey... HEY!
- I was just leaving. just leaving.
- Carla, this the guy?
CARLA: It's him.
No, you got me mistaken
with somebody else.
Oswald Danes, the child killer.
- No.
- If you don't want to be recognised,
don't put your face on TV!
Let's get him.
Officer! That kid!
He's...he's harassing me.
Oh, not fair, man.
You know who you got there?
- Look at him.
- It's a mistake.
- You should go home, sir.
- That's Oswald Danes.
Do you know what he said
about the girl,
the one he killed?
"She should have run faster."
That's what he said.
Go home right now.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I'm...just trying to get back to my motel.
Do you think you could give me a lift?
It's just off 278.
Yeah, get in.
Thank you.
DAN ES: What? Is there a problem here?
Officer?
You can get out, sir.
Ah, Shit.
All right. Of course.
Of course.
Here we go, huh?
Here we go.
Don't you worry, sir.
Nothing on your face.
You'll still be nice and handsome
for the TV.
You should have run faster, Oswald.
Are you saying the pharmaceutical
companies knew it was gonna happen?
Only one company - PhiCorp.
You OK?
My...my mother
had a massive stroke last year.
I...I had to make a choice.
God, if I'd just kept her alive
a little longer, if I'd been warned...
They even gave me their card.
PhiCorp.
Some woman called...Kitzinger.
She wants me to go
to some kind of private meeting.
Well, you know you have to go
and find out more.
I need to know what they're doing.
- Rex, that's your job, not mine.
- What?
Hey, listen, I'm serious.
I need you to do this.
You break in here,
threaten to expose me for helping you
and now you want me to,
what, spy for you?
Yeah, will you?
- No!
- PhiCorp knew, Vera.
OK? They could have warned us.
Think about your mother.
I mean, you let her die. She...
I'm taking a shower.
Let yourself out.
And I don't need to see you again.
Gwen, I had to call.
I thought of a thing.
- Are you drunk?
- A little.
You?
Some of us have to work.
Your turn to talk.
I know.
I was thinking...
...about how you're immortal...
...and I'm dying.
And what I wanted to say was...
...we're good, aren't we?
You and me.
A good team.
I missed you.
I was thinking, urn...
...if this had happened a bit sooner...
- I know.
- .--he 'd still be here,
Ian to.
Dead friends.
I'm sorry.
I wish he was here now.
Not much of a team, is it?
But we've still got each other.
You and me.
Just like the old days.
We don't need anyone, do we?
Sorry.
- We don't need Rex.
- I had to bounce a signal off Paraguay,
- but it's to say thanks.
-
Oh, my God. Rhys?
Oh, my God!
Can you see me?
I can see you. Can you see me?
Yes, I can see you.
A little bit too much of you,
not enough baby.
Put up the baby.
Give your mam a wave.
We don't need anyone.
Right, Gwen?
Gwen?
- Hey!
- Anwen.
- Hello, little sweetheart.
- It's your mummy, look! Your mam!
Hello, darling.
We're safe and we escaped.
We're fine, I promise.
I'll be home as soon as I can. I will.
Andy said he can move us
with police supervision back to Swansea,
so we 're all ready and waiting for you.
Hey, it's your mam! Hello, Mam!
Rough night, Oswald?
Oh, God.
What was it?
Was it Jill or...?
No, let me guess. Jillian?
Jilly. Jilly Kitzinger.
Told you you'd need me.
Now, we have a very important
meeting to go to,
so you can get cleaned up
on the plane to Dulles.
Dulles? why?
These are the times
that make men, Oswald.
So, it's your choice.
Stay where you are,
or stand up tall
and stride across the skin of the world.
Which is it?
Let's see...
If that's a promise of help...
you'd better deliver...
...Miss Jilly Kitzinger.
I will, sir.
I promise.
I'll hold you to it.
Lead on.
Yeah?
VERA: You left me your number
cos you knew I'd give in.
OK, I'm not the CIA,
I don't go undercover,
but...
maybe I can get you inside.
Yes!
I feel awful.
Which is amazing!
I thought we broke up.
Yeah, well, there's work to be done.
So, they just look like
contact lenses, huh?
Mm-hm. Look at the laptop.
They're the one piece
of Torchwood tech that I kept.
Huh!
It's like a camera, see? OK. Side...
- Huh!
- ...to side.
See?
That's very, very cool.
Where'd you get it from?
A distant moon of a distant star.
Ha, ha, ha
Really, where'd you get 'em from?
A distant moon of a distant star.
I am loving this hangover.
I knew mortality
would make life more intense.
Hey, don't touch my pills.
I need that for legitimate pain.
I need them too.
- You weren't impaled.
- You should've seen the other guy!
Ooh, that face!
Rex doesn't like his jokes too gay.
No, Rex doesn't like men
in their 40s acting like they're 20.
And we've got a winner. Now, hush.
Esther's sending me texts.
So we can communicate
with the I-5s just by typing.
REX: Hm.
Hello, Esther. I'm Gwen.
Yeah, but there's no sound.
Mm, but we've got lip-reading software.
Look at me.
- Right at me.
- Mm-hm.
Now say something.
My name is Rex Matheson,
representing
the Central Intelligence Agency.
COMPUTER: My name is Rex Matheson,
resenting
the Central Intelligence Ajenny.
All right, all right, that'll work.
I can get inside with those.
GWEN: Problem.
The I-5s, they're isomorphic -
biometrically tuned into me and me alone.
Seriously?
Mm-hm. If anyone is going on this mission,
it's got to be me.
- Yep.
- Huh?
- What?
-
We very much appreciate your coming.
PhiCorp knows how busy you must be.
No, I don't think this is right.
I was here to see a Miss Kitzinger?
No, this is the meeting.
I think you may know
some of these people.
Andy Collier from johns Hopkins.
Shelby Lewis, she made the shortlist
for the Lasker Prize.
OK.
We're starting in five.
- Oh, if you'll excuse me...?
- First door on your left.
Thank you.
- Where's Rex?
- No, I'm not Rex.
I know, hello! Long story.
Go back to the meeting
and keep Jilly Kitzinger there
for as long as you can. Go!
Are you giving me orders?
Yes, go!
- She did good, Dr Juarez.
- Yeah.
How'd you talk her into it?
Well, it's not exactly
a professional relationship.
Oswald Danes.
- What's he doing there?
- Tell her to follow Oswald.
No, no. No way.
Let her stay on the mission.
Gwen find out anything
about Oswald Danes?
Nothing special,
apart from being a monster.
He just chose the right day
to be executed on.
He's got nothing to do with this stuff.
- Ah.
- I'm sorry, no. I have been forgiven.
A substantial number of people
have forgiven me.
I can feel that in my heart in my guts.
And forgiveness, it's like a tide
or a storm. It clears the air.
I'm very lucky to have been forgiven
and I feel very...
I feel very blessed.
And I think of forgiveness as a cure.
Gentlemen, Mr Danes.
Yeah?
Who was that woman?
She works for me.
Are you at the meeting yet?
Yeah, but it's not a meeting.
It's some kind of...
presentation.
Right. Well, keep the line open.
I wanna hear.
Hello, and thank you for coming.
I'm Congressman Patrick Morganthall.
Some of you are listening to us
from Los Angeles...
A congressman?
...In Cleveland, DC, Dallas,
Singapore, Hang Kong...
- PhiCorp was ready, worldwide.
- If they knew about the miracle,
does that mean they caused it?
Our modern drug prescription system
has served us very well
for many decades,
but times have changed.
Times have changed a great deal.
The need for drugs
is far outstripping the access
to the people with the means
to prescribe them.
Something has got to change.
And that's why, later today,
I will be introducing legislation
to make all prescription drugs,
all painkillers, antibiotics,
almost all medications,
available without a prescription.
It'll, what, multiply sales by tenfold?
Psh! Try 1,000.
They're cashing in big time.
Where's Jack?
...and I am not just talking
about new laws.
I am talking about making
an entirely new society.
Now, this is a massive enterprise,
ladies and gentlemen.
But it's up to us.
- All of you are experts...
-jillyjust left.
Oh, shit!
Call her!
Call Jilly Kitzinger.
- Dr Juarez, hello.
- It's Vera.
I'm in the screening room.
I have some... Can you come here?
Can I ask you some questions?
Sure... Sure. Is everything all right?
You...you sound kind of shaky.
-
- Oh!
- Good work, Gwen Cooper!
-
You gonna get that?
It's not mine.
- They're calling Friedkin.
- Yeah, or they're calling us. Go, go.
Yeah?
Hello?
Who's there?
Who are you?
Who am I talking to?
Who is this?
Nothing.
It hits a vine.
They could've traced that handset.
Yeah, I know. Come on,
we gotta get the hell outta here,
outta DC.
Pack that stuff up quick.
What are you smiling for?
I think we got 'em worried.
Let's go.
And let's find out
where the hell Jack went.
OK, you ready for me?
Yeah, sure.
I'd apologise for being late,
but it wasn't my fault.
I was needed across town.
Still...
made it.
And...
this will be going out live, yes?
Can you tell me,
who's interviewing me?
Yeah, it's, uh...
Sod it!
I suppose a man like you
was always on his way.
You met with PhiCorp today. Why?
You'll have to ask them.
Did they mention
the name Jack Harkness?
Have you heard that name?
Never.
Why do you ask, Jack?
I figured if you cared that much
about the name, it was probably yours.
I just want you to talk.
What about?
I saw you on television,
saying you feel forgiven
for taking the life of a child.
That's a lie.
I know that's a lie.
How do you know that, Jack,
- with such certainty?
- Tell the truth!
The murder of Susie Cabina.
- You don't feel sorry at all.
- Oh...
The truth is,
she flaunted it.
Her innocence.
Most people,
they get hit or whatever,
it's hours
before the bruises rise up,
but they showed right away with her.
And it was like...
I was painting on her.
And she looked so beautiful.
I thought it couldn't get
any better than that.
But, oh, Jack,
I swear to you,
right then,
at the end,
I felt her life leave, and...
and she left through me.
Yeah!
You know that feeling?
I think you do.
And I relive it every single night,
because...
that was the best moment of my life.
Now I understand.
You're doing all this
cos you're searching for one thing.
One simple thing.
Execution.
World without death,
so you get to live.
And it's killing you.
Jack, what are you going to do
with that recording?
We're in a broadcast centre.
Figure I might broadcast it.
Excellent idea.
If only I didn't have to do this.
Boys!
- Take that recording off him.
- Argh! Ah!
I did visit PhiCorp, and they were
kind enough to offer me protection.
In exchange for what?
The message.
Don't hurt him.
Just...get rid of him.
It's nice to meet you, Jack Harkness.
Well, you can hurt him a little,
but not the face.
That's how it's done these days.
Let me be clear -
I'm not calling for free drugs
I'm calling for free access to drugs.
I want every American
to have the power
to be able to buy whatever they want
and need without a prescription.
Ah!
If that means that some drug companies
are gonna make a profit,
then maybe that just ensures
that they'll take better care of us.
Argh!
Because government has abandoned us.
Argh! Ah!
And I'm thinking
of companies like PhiCorp.
Aargh! Ah! Ah!
They'd never abandon us,
because they need us.
Aargh! Ah!
If we 're talking about medications,
I have to say
that I'm some what of an expert'.
I spent a lot of long years
in solitary confinement;
dangerous man -
companies like PhiCorp tried to help.
They put me on a drug reg/me
- with every drug known in the world...
- Did you see him in there?
Did you see Oswald Danes?
- Did you touch him?
- Did I what?
Oswald! Did you touch him?
...they stick with us.
And I'm asking you now
to join with me...
...in this great enterprise
as we all walk across the fragile skin
of this wide world...
together.
The future is now endless
and it's terrifying.
I'm offering you my hand
to walk on this long journey...
together.
Walk with me.
That's all I ask.
JACK: We need to find somewhere
to hide while we plan the assault'.
Wow! Look at the horizon!
We've reached the edge of America.
Hey, man. Believe.
Let me ask you something.
What is this "dead is dead" shit?
- Dead is dead.
- Dead is dead. That's me, huh?
The moment I lose my platform,
I get thrown back to the mob.
WOMAN: We are surrounded by people
who should have died.
VERA: There's just nothing more
we could do for them.
Segregation is vital and necessary.
I have risen with unending life.
These living deceased
should not have equal rights.
You've compromised the security
of the entire mission.
- They should be contained...
- I don't want to live forever.
...and then they should wait...
Torchwood keeps treating this
like it's a game.
...because I believe
their passage to the afterlife
has but paused
- and when this miracle ends...
- I'm so tired.
...Death will find them.
Their time will come,
and they will die.